Okay.
Let's start by creating a Java project.
Select Automotive Activity Java.
Select Language as Java.
Okay.
So now we have a basic Java project ready.
Let's now move this project to Aosp.
So this project is a simple Helloworld project at the moment.
So this project doesn't have any activities at the moment.
So let's add one activity, an empty activity task.
And here let's add a text book.
Name this as my Aosp Java project first aosp Java project.
Okay.
So now we have created a project in Android studio.
So as you already know, the build system for Android app development is Gradle.
So now we need to migrate this project to Aosp and ship it as part of the Aosp build.
So basically what we need to do is we need to copy the resource folder, Java folder and the manifest.
We need to ignore all the Gradle script files because Aosp is having a different build system.
So let's go ahead and do that.
So we need to basically migrate the Gradle project into this format, like this folder structure, right?
So the easiest way to do that is just copy one of the app.
Like in this case, I'll just copy the calendar app, copy, paste it here.
I have calendar copy now and let's go folder.
Rename this to my aosp char.
So I'm renaming the folder to my Aosp Java open this and now we could remove file sources source more
so removing the test.
So so basically we need to convert the Android project into this format.
It's pretty straightforward.
We just need to copy the source folder here, the source folder here and just replace this android manifest
here and then edit the Android dot beep file.
So let's do that.
So first thing, let's copy the source.
So I have opened the Android studio project in the left panel and the new folder which we created within
Aosp in the right panel.
So let's copy the source files to Aosp.
So this is our Gradle project, the Android Application Project.
So let's go into the source folder, main Java.
So we need to basically copy this chrome folder to the source folder here.
So right click, just copy.
Okay.
So the source folder is now here.
So we have the main activity or Java inside the my aosp Java module within within Aosp.
Okay.
So now let's copy the resource folder.
So this folder are delete this.
Copy this.
Here we have copied the resource folder and source folder here and now we have Android dot BP which
needs to be modified and we also need to copy the Android manifest or XML.
So let's copy that.
Let's first delete it from here.
Copied.
So we have copied the Android manifest XML source folder resource four.
So now we need to modify the Android dot beep file.
So let's switch to Visual Studio code.
So this is the so this is the newly created module.
We already copied the source and the source file.
We have main dot activity here and Android manifest.
So okay, so now let's modify Android dot BP file so we can leave the package as it is.
Change this name Android app to my aosp java and here in the sources we could just mention standard
Java.
So when we add a Kotlin project we need to mention start locating here.
So this project only has Java, so let's keep it as it is Java.
And then this is the resource folder SDK version, current target SDK version 2829.
Let's keep it as it is.
So you can also replace this with the information from Gradle in the project.
If you go to the build Gradle, you can just replace it with this value as well.
So for our case, let's keep it as it is and then optimize enabled false.
That's free object.
Just keep it as false and we can remove this library.
We don't have any dependency there.
So this is one important part.
So basically what our dependencies which are there in the original Android project that has to come
here, otherwise the build will fail.
So what you could do is go to Gradle.
So within Gradle we have these dependencies, right?
So basically we have to copy all these dependencies there.
So as we could see, it has the dependency on app compat, then we have the material libraries and then
the constraint layout and the unit test.
We are not moving the test folder so we can just ignore this for now.
So we need at least these three dependencies in the Android P file.
So let's replace this with these three dependencies.
So we need the lifecycle extension dependencies that combat dependencies and the material dependencies.
Okay, let's go ahead and compile in case if we are missing any further dependencies, then we could
add it.
So this is now done.
So I think now we are almost done with all the modules.
Now we need to add this project into the main build files.
That is, it depends on what build you are performing.
So in this case, I'm planning to add this to the automotive build.
So I need to basically modify the product packages of the automotive build Makefile.
So let's do that now.
So for the automotive build or the car product build, you can see all the product packages added under
the car dot file.
So you can see the car dialer car launcher system, UI, local media player, everything here.
So let's add our app as well here, copy this, paste this and please make a note.
We need to add the module name here.
So that means the name which you have given here to my aosp java based it here.
Save it now let's build it.
If there is any dependencies missing, then we could add, since this is a simple project, we all and
we only have a couple of dependencies, it's pretty straightforward.
But when you have a big project with lots of dependencies, that could become a little bit tricky.
So the only task is to find the right dependent modules and just add it under the static libs.
Now the build is successful, so let's run the emulator.
It started with the white data so that we show that we only have the factory apps in it.
Okay.
So here we go.
This is our app, my aosp java.
And chose the next my first Aosp Java project.
So the process is almost similar for the Kotlin projects as well, except that we need to make a minor
modification in the Android P file just to include the standard files.
We'll try out a Kotlin project in the later session.